Ryan Glass

Software Engineer

668 Bonanza Plain Avenue Henderson, NV 89011

7024268641

Ryanocanglass.phd@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Ryan is an expert at applying his programming skills to solve complex challenges. He comes to you with a track record of continually improving the way software works. In his current role, he is responsible for applying his technical know-how to manage and operate IT hardware, software and application solutions. On a personal level, he has the strong listening skills needed to acquire and comprehend a user's exact requirements. Right now, he would like to work for a company that offers its staff competitive pay, comprehensive benefits packages and outstanding future career advancement opportunities.

EDUCATION

University of Nevada Las Vegas, Las Vegas NV 2012 – 2016

3.8 GPA

Coursework Emphasis in Programming, Data Structures, Software Design, Systems Administration

EXPERIENCE

October 2019 - May 2020

Software Engineer (Contract) • Contracted Software Engineer • Nevada Skilled Nursing Development

- Complete wide range of software development and programming tasks on contract basis.
- Maintain accurate scheduling and meet objectives for simultaneous projects.
- Consult with company to determine user needs and design solutions.
- Analyze software usability and performance.
- Investigate any errors and reproduce issues to develop software fixes.
- Continuously document references to keep team up to date on changes to software.

Jan 2018 - August 2019

Web Developer (Contract) • Full Stack Web Developer • Clark County School District

Responsible for designing, developing and implementing web applications that satisfy complex and core business requirements.

- Develop high quality, performance, and reliable web applications
- Create features that work across multiple systems.
- Review code for quality, finding weaknesses and ensuring adherence to standards.
- Continuously document references to keep team up to date on changes to web applications.
- Identify tasks and functions that could be optimized through automation.
- Estimate time to develop and deploy new web application features.

August 2016 – December 2017 Junior Software Engineer • Java Developer • UnitX

- Collaborated with Senior Engineers to create clean interfaces and simple, intuitive interactions and experiences for technical support software.
- Aided in the design of embedded systems software by applying key principles of computer science, engineering, and mathematical analysis.
- Developed software solutions that addressed errors during production.
- Documented and advised all team members not in software development of changes

February 2016 – December 2016 Web Developer • Junior Web Developer • LV.NET

- Developed web interfaces to test and automate HR functions using RESTful API.
- Aided senior engineers with developing software solutions to errors within user interfaces and interactions.
- Use of GIT to submit work done to senior engineers to check on work completed.
- Managed and created tables through MySQL

TECHNICAL SKILLS

SQL, Python, Java, C++, C#, PHP, JavaScript, Angular, PowerShell.

COMMUNICATION

Accurately documents and communicates all software changes to team members through the use of updates, documentation, and emails to notify of upcoming changes to software.

REFERENCES

[Available upon request.]